I am a mixed method researcher with over five years' experience in technology and UX related research and design. I use both qualitative and quantitative methods, my expertise in design and development, and empathizing with users to help create products and services that bring values to people's lives.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES

Postdoctoral Researcher | Full-Time

Connections Lab, School of Interactive Arts & Technology, Simon Fraser University Aug. 2022 - Current | Surrey, B.C., Canada

Design and conduct *mixed methods* studies to understand technology design requirements for social collaborative activities; Mentor graduate students in their research, design, prototyping, and writing.

Graduate Research Assistant

GroupLens Lab, Computer Science & Engineering, University of Minnesota Aug. 2017 - Aug. 2022 | Minneapolis, MN, U.S.

Utilize both quantitative (e.g., experiment, survey, log analysis) and qualitative (e.g., interview, observation) methods to understand how people use current technologies and opportunities for technologies to better support their activities; Design and develop technology prototypes and evaluate them through various methods (e.g., field deployment, experiment, usability test). Some previous research works include:

- Scraped Reddit discussion data to understand how people leveraged technologies to play boardgames remotely during the pandemic; Recruited participants for indepth interviews to understand their technological practice and the effect on their social experience during the remote game play;
- Employed a user-centered design approach to design and develop an interactive visualization tool for helping designers and non-expert stakeholders understand trade-offs in machine learning models; Evaluated the tool via online experiment and expert interviews to understand the outcome.

Research Intern | Full-Time

EPIC Research Group, Microsoft Research

Jun. 2021 - Aug. 2021 | Remote, U.S.

Led the survey analysis to understand people's experience with multi-device usage when working from home; Developed a guiding framework summarizing multi-device usage patterns, presented, and helped other projects adopt the framework.

User Experience Specialist III | Full-Time

LexisNexis

Nov. 2016 - Jul. 2017 | Shanghai, China

Lead designer for cross-platform legal products from user research, ideation, design, testing to release; Collaborated closely with product and engineering teams throughout the product cycle and facilitated the communications between teams.

Interaction Designer | Full-Time

IA Collaborative

Sept. 2015 - June 2016 | Chicago, IL, U.S.

Collaborated with design researchers and visual designers to create omni-channel solutions and designed user experiences based on user needs and clients' requirements; Helped interaction design team utilize new tools by creating tutorials and teaching the team development knowledge.

EDUCATION

University of Minnesota

Ph.D. in Computer Science (HCI) Aug. 2017 - Aug. 2022

University of Washington

Master in HCI+D Sept. 2014 - Aug. 2015

St. Olaf College

B.A. Computer Science and Math Sept. 2010 - May 2014

SKILLS

User Research & Design

A/B Testing Contextual Inquiry **Diary Studies Experiment Design** Focus Group Heuristic Evaluation Interview

Journey Mapping Log Analysis Participatory Design Survey

Usability Testing Prototyping (Low-High Fidelity) Storyboarding Wireframing

Platforms & Tools

Adobe Creative Suite Axure / Principle dscout Figma / Sketch **JIRA** Qualtrics / SurveyMonkey Tableau UserTesting

Programming Languages

C/C++HTML&CSS Java JavaScript Processing / p5.js Python R SQL